Hello everyone, I am Adam.
This topic is the way for programmers from junior to senior engineer
Lets talk about the 10 stages of career promotion
if you are a new beginner, I hope to help you. Now follow me!
No matter which IDE you are using, you must learn to use hot keys
Yes, On the one hand is to pretend to bring you pleasure.
On the other hand is to save time. You are a coder be professional.
Don't click the mouse poke around.
If it is Linux VIM or NANO full of keyboard operation, it is not so neat
Basically 'copy and paste delete and undo exit and save'
If you have learnt 'Operation by Line, Find and Replace', you will be better
For more operations, please refer to the pdf file at the bottom of the video
Hotkey Guide.
As the saying goes, workers must first sharpen their tools to do their best
A wrench is good for an engineer whole life
The same is true for software engineers
From development tool IDE to make your own tool
It takes a lot of time to save the toolbox
Juniors must at least know the common tool
There is also a lot of content about tools.
Chat later in the future
In the Java world
Google's Guava core library
Apache's Commons component
Spring's Utils framework
These tools can save a lot of cumbersome operations
For example, Guava's collection tool package
StringUtils Can solve the problem of string operation in the development process
BeanUtils Can quickly make entity copies
what? Never heard of it?
Colleagues need to change another welcome when they say hello tomorrow
Hi Bro! long time no see! Writing bugs aha?
Distributed version control system
Strictly It's not just a code management software
It is an idea A file backup idea
Let's revisit this from the example of protecting eggs
If you have a basket of eggs
How do you protect and eat it within the shelf life What issues do you need to care?
Is the basket strong and durable? If the basket is being broken What can I do?
Whether to carry the basket? Eat eggs at noon or at work at night?
Do I need to number the eggs?
If I take the eggs in the wrong order and eat them?
Do I need a camera on the basket to catch the eggs change?
......
May not take into account so many problems in life
But in the programing world Everything is data
Missing is missing
Do you remember your earliest camera phone,where are the photos you took？
Important information must be very careful:
Automatic multiple backup and Get it anytime, anywhere
Git, An automatic backup history、Collaboration and distribution、Anywhere、Code management software
是Linus从自己的工具箱里拿出来的
你现在所用的网络硬盘、百度云、谷歌磁盘、OneDrive
都和代码管理软件 Git 如出一辙
目的都是管理你的文件（代码）让你在所能想到的异常突发事件中
保证文件（代码）的可用性、安全性、协同性达到平衡
最早编程都是面向过程的 后来感觉过程一长就显的没有层次分类
面向对象概念横空出世
想当初做为新手的我 对这个概念也琢磨了好几天
后来发现其实就是教你 怎么把一样地东西放一在块儿
而达到复用的目的
这不就是分类整理吗
再后来 JS从前端走向后台
闭包 匿名方法 这些概念再次高大上起来
总结下来其实就是 大部分面向对象
局部面向过程 能隐藏的就别暴露
人生苦短 多用闭包
自从用了SVN 再也不怕一个人干不完活了
自从用了Git 再也不要保留注释掉的代码了
一定要把你自己注释掉的代码删除
因为30天后 你自己根本不知道注释它的原因
只要曾经推过git 就大胆删除过期的代码吧
我在团队中的代码提交贡献量
就出现过每增加1行 删除5行的记录
一名优秀的程序员
对技能的要求真不是第一位的
逻辑性才是 开发就是这样
有可能10分钟的代码量 要调试3个小时
调试不光是试错 更多地是理清来龙去脉
要记住 没有无缘无故的故障
逻辑清晰的要求不光是对技术领域
也包含业务领域
这件事为什么要这么干 这个业务为什么要这么实现
一定要在内心 多问一句 为什么
还记得前面所说的工具类吧
工具类就是一次封装的标准示范
程序员从初级到高级
就是从使用别人的工具到自己开发工具的过程
做程序和做木匠是一样的
自己打造的工具才符合自己的人体工程学
业务代码实现 一定要想尽办法做到纯粹
一个组件 只解决一个小小的问题
这里说的懒不是让我们少干活
而是把要干的活 精细化
最后做一个代码的指挥者 躺着就把活干完了
一分钟教你识别程序员
格子衬衫牛仔裤 黑框眼镜双肩包
当然这里不教你怎么捯饬自己
只是为了表达一下强迫症
能用tab的别用空格！
左花括号千万别换行！！
注释一定要与代码对齐！！！
一段业务处理完了一定要空一行！！！！
当你感觉自己对这些要求 已追求到发狂的时候
作为高级程序员 你一定要看接下来的提示
曾经一个人站在git提交记录面前
曾经默默的打开队友的代码 再关上
曾经优化写法 修正格式 再撤回
终于 释然了 放弃了 算了不生气
人都是自由的 就像你管不了别人吃穿品味一样
对队友的磨难就是对自己的不公
大胆的犯错吧
有时弯路会让你跑的更快 再次愉快的做好朋友的 不吵架
一定要允许新手犯错 过早优化是万恶之源
当你处在关键岗位上时
大大小小的会议是跑不掉了
早会 晚会 总结会
培训会 需求会 技术研讨会
演示会 对接会 需求沟通会
刚开始你会感觉这些会议 大量浪费自己的工作时间
当你慢慢觉悟后会发现
这是你进入管理岗的开始
会议能让你深入业务
突然认识到自己原来是一个优秀的产品经理
与此同时 准备一个好看一点的水杯
最好多装一点水
毕竟摸键盘时总是忘记喝水
趁这个机会 多喝点水吧
1665年，牛顿到乡下躲避瘟疫
自我隔离 不串门 不逛街
不参加聚会
感悟出了人生与科学的大道理
新冠疫情刚好给了我们这样的机会，
独处能让我们淡定下来多思考。
不要只做一个程序员
做一些重要的东西
做一些有意义的事情
做一些能解决问题的事情
你是问题的解决者 创造者 创新者
不是编程者 编程只是你在完成创新的工具
去解决实际的问题吧
下期见